JACOB PRUDENT

FULLSTACK WEB DEVELOPER

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/jacob-prudent-a043a389/ ↑ https://github.com/prudent

SKILLS

SKILLS: HTML/CSS, LESS, React, Node.js, Tailwind, Python, Knex, Responsive Web Design, Biochemistry

PROJECTS

Sorting Hat Mar. 2020 - May 2020

Quiz web application to sort prospective tech students into relevant tracks of education. I served primarily as a Front End Developer on this project, following the UX designer's plans pixel perfect. React · Tailwind · Redux · Node.js

Game of Life June 2020 - June 2020

Implemented Conway's Game of Life individually over the course of a few days. Purpose of this project was to have state update dynamically following clear logical rules matching a simple algorithm. React · Styled Components.

Africa Connected Feb. 2020 - Feb. 2020

Implemented a simple online marketplace with a team. Served as one of the React developers on this team, responsible for state, and UI overhaul. React · Material UI · useContext

EDUCATION

Lambda School Oct. 2019 - Current

Endorsement 2020

Brigham Young University - Idaho

Bachelors of Science in Biochemistry 2016

Aug. 2013 - July 2016

EMPLOYMENT

Lambda School, Section Lead, Remote

June 2020 - Current

- Mentored eleven Team Leads each of which oversaw and assisted educating five to twelve students.
- Provided troubleshooting and support for a diverse assortment of applications.
- Guided, consulted, and facilitated students in their Lambda Labs experience

Tyson Foods, *Microbiologist*, Richland, WA

Sept. 2018 - Sept. 2019

- Tested product and environmental samples for food-borne pathogens such as e coli (ECH7) and listeria species
- Updated the laboratory information system with test results, and promptly notified QC and plant management of positive results
- Handled laboratory preparation work such as media preparation, inventory

Santa Cruz Biotechnology, Research Assistant, Ketchum, ID

Aug. 2017 - Aug. 2018

- Performed and analyzed micro-array screening of hybridomas for antibody production
- Assisted in western blot developments
- Assisted in assay design and improvement
- Handled laboratory preparation work such as chemical stripping, aminosilane coating and solution preparation